Nora England Papers
Nettie Lee Benson Latin American Collection
- Series II: Bound Publications by Others
  - Subseries II: Collected Publications
    - Pi-najuuyaa iquiituuhuaaca cuhuasiini, Vamos a escribbir el idioma iquito, Segunda edición, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Metodo Funcional for Learning Mayan Languages, book and CD, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Tejiendo el Corazón de Nuestros Ancestros, Gobierno de Guatemala, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Bajo la Sombra de la Santa Montaña: La Historía de las Comunidades de Población en Resistencia de la Sierra, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Cuadernos winaq, vol. 5. Winaq: Kynaab'il / Kyna'b'il Qxe'chil, Fundamentos del Pensamiento Maya, 2011 April (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Subseries III: Newsletters and Reports
    - Subsubseries: Newsletters
      - Guatemalan Church in Exile, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Noticias de Guatemala, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Guatemala News in Brief, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - The Global Reporter, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Boletín de Lingüística, 1987-1998 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Mayan Linguistics Newsletter, 1990-1999 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Guatemala Scholars Network News, 1991-2001 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - The Society for the Study of the Indigenous Languages of the Americas Newsletter, 1992-2001 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Subsubseries: Reports (Box 6)
      - Reports on Guatemalan Earthquake, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Interamerican Foundation Reports, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Witness to Political Violence in Guatemala, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Guatemala: A Government Program of Political Murder, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Subseries IV: Journals
    - Mayan Studies I, No. 5, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Diné Bizaad Náníl'iih: Navajo Language Review, Vol.1 Num. 1, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Latinamericanist, Vol. 9, Numbers 1-5, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Latinamericanist, Vol. 10, Numbers 1-4, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Texas Linguistic Forum, No 3-4, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Florida Journal of Anthropology, Volume 1, No. 2, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Pablo Mendoza, Fortunato, and Una Canger, Tne::l U'j Kye Xja:l Todo Sant Cuchumatan, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - The New Republic: Guatemala Bleeds, 1983 April 11 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Aprendamos el Idioma Mam, No. 1, 1984 June (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Hemisphere, Fall 1988 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Función, No, 15-16, 1994 December (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Boletín Internacional de Lenguas y Culturas Amerindias, No. 1, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Cultura de Guatemala, 1995-1999 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Segundo Congreso de Estudios Mayas, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Cultura de Guatemala, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - New Perspectives in Mayan Linguistics, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Subseries V: Children's Published Material
    - Ri Chemaj Ya'nuya Ri Narayb'ej and cassette tape, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - La Poza de los Deseos and cassette tape, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Pérez López, Enrique, El K´ox (El niño que se tranformó en sol), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Pérez López, Enrique, Yalan Bek'et (Bájate carne), 1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Diseño de Reforma Educativa Runuk'ik jun K'ak'a Tijonïk, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Ministerio de Educacion Kaqchikel, K'iche', and Castellano textbooks, second grade, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Lhachefwenyaj toj Wichita Lhomtes: Adaptación del libro N'atetshan Wichita lhaämtes, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Tsalanawu activity books, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - El Conejo y el coyote, 2016 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Subseries VI: Proyecto Lingüístico Francisco Marroquín (PLFM) Published Material
    - Guaján Rodríguez, José O., Gramatica del Idioma Kaqchikel, 1988 December (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Suy Tum, Benifacio D., Gramatica del Idioma K'iche', 1988 December (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Lainez Ortiz,, Alonzo, Gramatica del Idioma Mam, 1988 December (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Cuc Caal, Alfonso, Gramatica del Idioma Q'echi', 1988 December (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - PLFM, Cursos Linguisticos, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Lectura y Gramatica, PLFM Textbook, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Subseries VII: Bound Linguistic Works by Others
    - Diaz Cuyasa, Hermenegildo, Ema Llona Yareja, Jaime Pacaya Inuma, and Ligia Inuma Inuma, "Diccionario Bilingüe Iquito - Castellano y Castellano - Iquito, "Tomo I, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Diaz Cuyasa, Hermenegildo, Ema Llona Yareja, Jaime Pacaya Inuma, and Ligia Inuma Inuma, "Diccionario Bilingüe Iquito - Castellano y Castellano - Iquito, "Tomo II, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Diaz Cuyasa, Hermenegildo, Ema Llona Yareja, Jaime Pacaya Inuma, and Ligia Inuma Inuma, "Diccionario Bilingüe Iquito - Castellano y Castellano - Iquito, "Tomo I, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Diaz Cuyasa, Hermenegildo, Ema Llona Yareja, Jaime Pacaya Inuma, and Ligia Inuma Inuma, "Diccionario Bilingüe Iquito - Castellano y Castellano - Iquito, "Tomo II, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Diaz Cuyasa, Hermenegildo, Ema Llona Yareja, Jaime Pacaya Inuma, and Ligia Inuma Inuma, "Diccionario Bilingüe Iquito - Castellano y Castellano - Iquito,", 2006 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Diaz Cuyasa, Hermenegildo, Ema Llona Yareja, Jaime Pacaya Inuma, and Ligia Inuma Inuma, "Iquiituhuaaca saaquiinica: cuentos, relatos, e historias del pueblo iquito, "Tomo I, 2006 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Kaufman, Terrence, "The Meso-American Calendar: The Day-Names,", 1989 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Kaufman, Terrence, "Comparative Mayan Verb Morphology,", undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Series III: Works by Nora England
  - Subseries I: Theses
    - Aymara Verbal Derivational Suffixes, Draft, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Aymara Verbal Derivational Suffixes, Draft, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Aymara Verbal Derivational Suffixes, Draft, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Aymara Verbal Derivational Suffixes, Final Draft, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Aymara Verbal Derivational Suffixes, Master's Thesis, University of Florida, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Mam Grammar in Outline, PhD Thesis, University of Florida, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Subseries II: Articles and Papers
    - Education and Anthropology Linguistics, New Voices in Education, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - The Independent Verb Phrase in Mam, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Mam Text, International Journal of American Linguistics Native American Texts Series, Volume 1, Number 1, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Mam Directionals and Verb Semantics, UCLA American Indian Studies Center, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Verb Categories in Mam, Florida Journal of Anthropology, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Mam Directionals and Verb Semantics, Mayan Linguistics, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - The Development of the Mam Person System, International Journal of American Linguistics, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - A Type of Mam Emphasis, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Space as a Mam Grammatical Theme, In Papers in Mayan Linguistics, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Orthographies for Mayan Languages, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Ergativity in Mamean (Mayan) Languages, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Eating in Mam, a Mayan Language, Journal of Mayan Linguistics, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Linguistics and Foreign Aid, The Aymara Language in its Social and Cultural Context, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Ergativity in Mamean (Mayan) Languages, International Journal of American Linguistics, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Speaking Mam, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Diccionario Mam de San Ildefonso Ixtahuacan, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Ergativity in Mamean (Mayan) Languages, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Introduction, Bilingualism: Social Issues and Policy Implications, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Ergativity in Mamean (Mayan) Languages, International Journal of American Linguistics, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - "Unofficial" Refugees in Chiapas, Cultural Survival, Volume 8, Number 5, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Question Formation in Kusaal, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - The Elaboration of Directionals in Mamean, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Control and Complementation in Kusaal, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Bosquejo del Mam de Ostuncalco, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Papers in the Structure of Kusaal, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Cakchiquel/Mam Dialectology: Current Research, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - El Mam: Hacia una definición gramatical del idioma, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Mamean Voice, Synactic and Narrative Considerations, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Passive and Voice, Mam Voice, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Un Analisis de las Encuestas Dialectales Recopilados por el Proyecto Linguistico Francisco Marroquin, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Comparative Mam (Mayan) Clause Structure: Subordinate vs. Main Clauses, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Hacia una Definición del Idioma Mam, Boletín de Linguistica, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Control and Complementation in Kusaal, Current Approaches to African Linguistics, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Un Analysis de las Encuestas Dialectales Recopiladas por el Proyecto Linguistico Francisco Marroquin: Los Casos de Cakchiquel y Mam, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - A la Vida de los Idiomas Maya, Boletin de Linguistica, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Variation in Mayan Narrative, Anthropological Linguistics, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Comparing Mam (Mayan) Clause Structures. Subordinate vs. Main Clauses, International Journal of American Linguistics, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Idiomas Mayas en Guatemala, LASA XIV, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Mam Voice, Passive and Voice, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Variation in Mayan Narrative, Anthropological Linguistics, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - El Desarollo de los fonemas tch, tch', sh, en el Mam de Todos Santos, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - La Ergatividad en las Idiomas Mayas, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Comparing Mam (Mayan) Clause Structures: Subordinate Versus Main Clauses, International Journal of American Linguistics, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - The Grammaticalization of Discourse Constraints in K'ichean Mayan Languages, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Changes in Basic Word Order in Mayan Languages, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - El Mam Semejanzas y Diferencias Regionales, Lecturas Sobre La Linguistica Maya, CIRMA, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Changes in Basic Word Order in Mayan Languages, International Journal of American Linguistics, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - La Ergatividad en los Idiomas Mayas, Winak, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Lengua y Definición étnica entre los Mayas de Guatemala, Proyectos de Investigación, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Doing Mayan Linguistics in Guatemala, Language, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Agreement and Split Agreement in Mayan Languages, Leiden University, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - The Role of Language Standardization in Revitalization, Mayan Cultural Activism in Guatemala, 1993-1995 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - La Historia de las Vocales en los Idiomas Mayas, Boletín Linguistica, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Linguistics for Indigenous American Languages, Mayan Examples, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - The Role of Language Standardization in Revitalization, Mayan Cultural Activism in Guatemala, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Topicalización, enfoque y énfasis, Cultura de Guatemala, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Mayan Efforts Toward Language Preservation, Endangered Languages, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - El papel de la estandarización idiomática en la revitalización, activismo cultural maya, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Commentary: Further Rhetorical Concerns, Journal of American Linguistics, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Issues in the Comparative Argument Structure Analysis in Mayan Narratives in Preferred Argument Structure, 2002-2003 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Maya Linguistics, Linguistics and the Politics of Identity. Texas Linguistics Society, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Mayan Language Revival and Revitalization Politics: Linguistics and Linguistic Ideologies, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Mayan Language Revival and Revitalization Politics: Linguistics and Linguistic Ideologies, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Training Speakers of Indigenous Languages of Latin America at a US University, Language Documentation and Description, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Adjectives in Mam, Adjective Classes, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - El Papel de Palabras Afectivas para Avanzar la Narración en Mam (Mayan), VIII Encuentro Internacional de Linguistica en el Noreste, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - ¿Qué tan cierto es lo que digo? Evaluación de la información en Mam, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Guatemala: Language Situation, Encyclopedia of Language and Linguistics, 2005-2006 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - El Papel de Palabras Afectivas en la Narración en Mam, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Marking Aspect and Mood and Inferring Time in Mam, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - The Influence of Mayan Speaking Linguists on the State of Mayan Linguistics, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - To Tell a Tale: The Structure of Narrated Stories in Mam, a Mayan Language, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Cláusulas de inflexión reducida en Mam, 2007-2010 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Tópico y Enfoque de Nominales en K'ichee', 2009 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Logros y desafíos de la Lingüística Maya, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Revisiting Topic and Focus in Kichee', 2009 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - To Tell a Tale: The Structure of Narrated Stories in Mam, Interational Journal of American Linguistics, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Mam: Alineamiento en Cláusulas Ditransitivas, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Nominal Topic and Focus in K'ichee, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Mayan Languages, Oxford Bibliographies in Linguistics, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Plurality Agreement in Some Eastern Mayan Languages, International Journal of American Linguistics, 2011 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - From Possessive Marker to Topic Marker in Mam, 2012 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Logros y desafíos de la Lingüística Maya, 2013 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Mayan Languages, Oxford Research Encyclopedia, 2017 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Mayan Languages, Oxford Bibliographies in Linguistics, 2017 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Training Language Activists to Support Endangered Languages, Oxford Handbook of Endangered Languages, 2018 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - A la Vida de las Idiomas Mayas, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Variation in Mayan Narrative, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - El Mam: Semejanzas y Diferencias Regionales, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Diccionario Mam de San Ildefonso Ixtahuacán, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Subseries III: Conferences Presentations
    - Person in Mam, American Anthropological Association, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Mam Directionals: Some Notes on Semantics, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Mam Transitivty, American Anthropological Association, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Linguistic and Cultural Categories in the Mam Area, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - A Type of Mam Emphasis, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The Discourse Function of -ee in Mam, American Anthropological Association, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - The Structure of Couplets in Mam Narrative, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Introduction to Bilingualism: Social Issues and Policy, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - The Elaboration of Directionals in Mamean, 15th Conference on African Linguistics, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Language and Ethnic Definition Among Guatemalan Mayans, American Anthropological Association, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - The Grammaticalization of Discourse Constraints in K'ichean Mayan Languages, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Linguistic Contributions to Prescriptive Grammars, American Anthropological Association, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Mayan Progressive, Congreso Internacional de Americanistas, 1991-1993 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Linguistics for Speakers of Endangered Languages, American Anthropological Association, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Mayan Efforts Towards Language Preservation, Endangered Languages Conference, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Topicalización, enfoque y énfasis, 1996-2004 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Contributions of Maya Linguists to Identity Politics and Linguistics, Conference on Language, Communities, States and Global Culture, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Topicalización, Enfoque y Enfasis, Primer Congreso de Estudios Mayas, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Ergatvidad y la Extracción del agente en varios idiomas Mayas, Cuarto Congreso de Mayistas, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Distinguiendo idiomas y dialectos Mam y Teko, Tercer Congreso de Estudios Mayas, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Turning the Tables on Language Loss, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - What Mayan Antiquity Means to Modern Maya, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Mayan Language Ideologies, Linguistics, and Revitalization, American Anthropological Association, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Mayan Language Revival and Revitalization Politics, American Anthropological Association, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Distinguiendo idiomas y dialectos Mam y Teko, Encuentro Pueblos y Fronteras, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Combate de Ideologias Linguisticas en Guatemala, Cuarto Congreso de Estudios Mayas, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Maya Linguists, Linguistics, and Politics as Identity, SALSA, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - El tiempo/aspecto en la narración de cuentos en Mam, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Language and Cuture Revitalization Among Contemporary Mayas, 10th European Maya Conference, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Cohesión Temporal en Mam, 6th Congreso de Estudios Mayas, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Politicas y Planificacion Linguistica en Guatemala, 20th Aniversario del Instituto de Linguistica y Educacion, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Clausulas no finitas en Mam, 9th Encuentro Internacional Linguistica en el Noreste, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Los Usos y Funciones de los Marcadores Ergativos en Mam, CILA, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - The Role of Linguistics in Indigenous Revitalization and Teaching, STILA, 2008 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Logros y Desafios de Linguistica Maya, Keynote address, 8th Congreso de Estudios Mayas, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - The Impact of the PLFM on Linguistics, SSILA, 2017 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Subseries IV: Books
    - Handwritten Notes for A Grammar of Mam, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - A Grammar of Mam, Draft, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Introduction to A Grammar of Mam, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Handwritten Introduction to A Grammar of Mam, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - La Autonomía de los Idiomas Mayas: Historia e Identidad, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - The Mayan Languages, Edited by Nora England, Judith Aissen, and Roberto Zavala Maldonado, 2016-2017 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - A Grammar of Mam, a Mayan Language, pre-print page proofs, 1983 (Box 21)
    - Maya' Chii', Los Idiomas Mayas de Guatemala, 2017 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Subseries V: Reviews and Book Notes written by Nora England
    - Review by Nora England of "Tzeltal Phonology and Morphology,", 1971 (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Review by Nora England of "The Development of the Mam Person System,", 1976 (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - Review by Nora England of "Jacaltec: The Structure of Jacaltec,", 1977 (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - Review by Nora England of Jacaltec: The Structure of Jacaltec" in the American Anthropologist, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 52)
    - Review by Nora England of Is God an American? An Anthropological Perspective on the Missionary Work of the Summer Institute of Linguistics, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Review by Nora England of "Of Shoes and Ships and Sealing Wax,", 1981 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Review by Nora England of Diccionario Tzotzil de San Andrés con Variaciones Dialectales, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Review by Nora England of Diccionario Tzotzil de San Andrés con Variaciones Dialectales, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Review by Nora England of The Foreign Impact on Lowland Mayan Language and Script, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Review by Nora England of Handbook of Middle American Indians, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Review by Nora England of Harvest of Violence, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Review by Nora England of "International Encylopedia of Linguistics,", 1993 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Review by Nora England of "Lecturas Sobre Linguistica Maya,", 1993 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Review by Nora England of "The Green Book of Language Revitalization in Practice,", 2000 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Review by Nora England of "Relatively Speaking: Language, Thought, and Kinship Among the Mopan Maya,", 2001 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Review by Nora England of "Can Threatened Languages Be Saved?,", 2001 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Review by Nora England of "Making Dictionaries: Preserving Indigenous Languages of the Americas,", 2003 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Review by Nora England of "K'iche': A Study in the Sociology of Language,", 2003 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Review by Nora England of "The Languages of the Andes,", 2004 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Subseries VI: Reviews of Nora England's Work
    - Reviews, Grammar of Mam by Nora England, 1983-1985 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Subseries VII: Unpublished Works
    - A Hierarchy of Parellelism, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Mayan Language for the Encyclopedia of Latin American History, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Panorama lingüístico del mundo indígena precolombino en Guatemala hacia 1520, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Ergativity and the Extraction of Agents in Mam, K'ichee and Q'anjob'al, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Distinguishing Languages: Mam and Teko, 1999-2002 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - From Posessive Marker to Topic Marker in Mam, 2012 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Series IV: Teaching and Academic Research Materials
  - Subseries I: Bryn Mawr
    - Student Notebook, Bryn Mawr, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Subseries II: University of Florida, 1970-1975
    - Aymara Tape Transcript 1Y, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Teacher's Manual, Aymara Ar Yatiqanataki, 1969-1971 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Teacher's Manual, Aymara Ar Yatiqanataki, 1969-1971 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Teacher's Manual, Aymara Ar Yatiqanataki, 1969-1971 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - A Partial Analysis of the Morphology of Aymara, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Seminar in Linguistic Field Methods, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Aymara Language Materials, Aymar Ar Yatiqanataki-part 1, 1969-1971 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Aymara Language Materials, Aymar Ar Yatiqanataki-part 2, 1969-1971 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Aymara Language Materials, Aymar Ar Yatiqanataki-part 3, 1969-1971 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Aymara Grammatical Sketch-part 1, 1969-1971 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Aymara Grammatical Sketch-part 2, 1969-1971 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Aymara Grammatical Sketch-part 3, 1969-1971 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Aymara Newsletters, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Aymara Scripts and Vocab, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Aymara TG Tree, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Instituto de Lengua y Cultura Aymara (ILCA), 1973 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Misc. Work on Aymara, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Aymara Scripts, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Aymara Phonology Scripts, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Aymara Script VII, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Aymara Material, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Andean Vocab, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Dialogue IX, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Indian Conference, Florida, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Subseries: PLFM
    - Peace Corps, Language Proficiency Interview Report, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Ministro de Educación, Letter to the American Anthropological Association, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - New Mayan Languages in Guatemala: Sacapultec, Sipacapa, and Others, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 8)